

J +91 8872409191

in Gurwinder-singh-2277a4137

Gurwinder91

S live:somal.gurwinder7

Bengaluru, IN

SKILLS

Tools and Technologies

ASP.NET Core Web API

Angular

PWA

Javascript

C#/TS

EF Core

Angular Material

Html/Flexbox/SCSS

MS SQL

Testing Frameworks

Karma/Jasmine

X-Unit

Design and Architecture

Microservices

CQRS

Industry knowledge

AWS

Docker

VSTS/Git

Agile/Nexus

LANGUAGE

English

 \odot

Hindi

Punjabi

Gurwinder Singh Somal ASP.NET Full Stack Developer

An experienced Software Engineer working primarily in ASP.NET core Web APIs, Angular and AWS from last 4.3 years. I am passionate about my work and always keen to learn from others.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

TransferMate Global Payments &

Aug, 2018 - Present

Bengaluru, IN

Currently, working with TransferMate Global Payments. It provides smarter way to send and receive money internationally. Created Angular 7 architecture using custom NPM libraries, Angular Material and Flex layout. Developed Microservices based architecture in backend with SQS and lambda as a message broker. Created docker images for the backend services and angular application. Used TDD approach in all services to develop bug free application. Setup AWS ECS Fargate, S3, SQS and lambda for Dev, QA and Staging environments to deploy application using VSTS CI/CD release pipeline. Used Nexus Framework for project management and continuous delivery of project.

Angular Developer

ONE BCG &

Feb, 2018 - Aug, 2018

Mohali, IN

Allied Wallet, a globally leading provider of online payment processing, multicurrency merchant services, and a PCI Level 1 secured payment gateway. I developed code to enable a new merchant in the NextGen system on acquirer side to allow the payments from specific card provider. Daily meetings with onshore and Allied Wallet engineering team via calls and emails to give status updates. Developed modules using Angular 6, C#, MVC. Extensive use of Web API through abstraction at different tiers of application. Used Code Analysis and StyleCop for peer code review.

ASP.NET Developer

Ariel Software Solutions &

Jan, 2016 - Jan, 2018

Mohali, IN

I have worked on multiple projects with different domains by using ASP.NET MVC 5, ASP.NET core, Angular 2, MS SQL, VSTS, Jquery and Javascript. I was involved in communication with clients on a daily basis to understand and brainstorming of project requirements. Developed Angular 2 application from scratch by consuming web API.

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Information Technology

Punjab Technical University &

Sep, 2009 - April, 2013

Mohali, IN

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Travelled to QATAR for Qatar ministry of justice project handled by EBLA Computer Consultancy from 20 July, 2017 - 20 Jan, 2018. I have worked as Angularjs Developer on official application.

INTERESTS

Running

Football

Cricket

Music

Cooking